

Contact

+447487248276

Email Link

a Lowestoft, Suffolk

GitHub

o Portfolic

E Troobouse

Skill Key

Expert

Proficient

Intermediate

Basic

Testimonials

Kayleigh Hall

Development Manager

"Testimonial to be provided by developer

."

Tessa Dempsey

Project Manager

"Testimonial to be provided by project manager

Aaron Smith

Junior Web Developer

Summary

Entry-level ICT Web Developer Full-Stack student with excellent ability within PHP, HTML, JavaScript (SASS – CSS3). Additionally, I have been attending a sixmonth award-winning scion program provided by the Netmatters company which trains web developers and software coders using in-house experts to enable workplace ready skills. Moreover, the Netmatters company has trained me in web development and c# to a very high-standard of full-stack and backend knowledge.

I have the ability to use perspective-taking and analytical expertise to identify problems and find solutions to address the situation. I can work well under pressure and adhere to strict deadlines.

Skills

HTML5 450+ hours

Several years of experience both personally and professionally. Comfortable with semantic markup and general structuring.

JavaScript 450+ hours

Able to use vanilla JavaScript as well as jQuery and AJAX. Comfortable with using external libraries.

Java 240+ hours

Used Java to create small programs for my studies; conditional statements and loops.

Laravel 240+ hours

Understand how to install and manage the framework.

Jupyter Notebook 200+ hours

I have used Jupyter Notebook throughout my Data Science certification course with IBM.

CSS3 450+ hours

Able to manage layouts with both Flexbox and CSS Grid. Comfortable with using SCSS.

PHP 450+ hours

Basic knowledge of the language, including an understanding of the core features. Good understanding of both procedural and object-oriented PHP.

SQL 450+ hours

Knowledge of CRUD actions while working in PHP. I attended a small course on Database Administration at the Norwich UEA.

Git 240+ hours

Used frequently while working on projects.

Treehouse

Treehouse is an online learning community, featuring videos covering a number of topics from basic HTML to C# programming, iOS development, data analysis, and more. By completing courses users can earn points, allowing them to track their progress and see how much they've covered certain areas.

Total Score WRITE SCORE teamtreehouse.com/USERNAME and link to

Introduction to Scion Coalition Scheme

The Scion Coalition Scheme is an intensive, specially tailored training program being run by Netmatters in order to give willing candidates the opportunity to enter the industry as web developers. Under the supervision of senior web developers, scions generally aim to complete training within six to nine months. The course is intensive and therefore the level of learning achieved is extensive in a short space of time.

Experience

Riverside Business Centre

Financial Services Admin. 2020 - 2020

- Data entry including spreadsheets (Excel) and outlook.
- SQL database queries [basic] SQL database queries which included retrieving and updating information within the database.

Hoseasons

Inbound Sales Consultant 2018 - 2019

- Sales Consultant for the first point of contact for customers to book their holiday. Responsible for handling inbound calls, and booking holidays.
- Working on computer system inputting customers' info/details i.e. holiday search & payment details.

Education

2018-Present

Scion Coalition Scheme

- Undertook an intensive, specially tailored training program under the supervision of senior web developers in the industry. This course is 40 hours per week and simulates employment as a developer to ensure the trainee is prepared for full time employment.
- Studied front-end and back-end development including UI/UX design, mobile development, object-oriented programming and databases.
- Created a web game to advertise the Scion Coalition Scheme on the Netmatters website. This included coding the game logic in HTML5 and JavaScript as well as developing graphical assets to client specification.
- Acted as technical lead for a small team developing the brand and website for an 'events management company' as part of a group project.

2018-2022 East Coast College / Diploma Level 5.

- Diploma in Computing and Mathematics.
- Modules: Object-oriented Java programming, Algorithms, data structures, and computability, Web technologies, mathematics.

2016-2016 Zend / PHP Training and PHP Certification.

- PHP Fundamentals I and II.
- Create database-driven web applications similar to the course applications. Leverage object-oriented programming (OOP) techniques in your applications.

Hobbies

Data Science / Sports Analytics

I use Data Science (K-means clustering algorithm) to help design and develop my Fantasy Football Team. Moreover, I have designed graphic illustrations to highlight which players I should pick based on various factors.

Coding Video Games using JavaScript

I subscribe to online courses using Udemy and Coursera to learn how to code small video games using JavaScript. I enjoy the projects and materials available and take great fun completing coding challenges.